The.
Yeah, I think there's a...
Hey, I...
Oh, sorry, I think Thomas, yeah,
please Thomas, go ahead.
I have one thought to add to that. Yeah,
please go ahead.
Yeah, there's a couple of things.
So just to give everybody a brief,
I know we've talked quite a bit about it
and decisions were made while I was on
vacation,
but we went back through them again
yesterday.
Because of the process that Manuela has
created of generating React UI components
from
from Figma designs and the process that
we feel that's going to be easier to
continue with doing React than to try to
switch to Angular,
just because it would require quite a bit
of reworking of the process itself.
So we've kind of made that decision. Now,
that doesn't mean that everything that
we've already done,
we're going to initially redo.
You know,
there are some things that we've built in
Angular that we're going to leave for now.
And we'll figure out ways to route them
from the React homepage that we've built
so far. But, you know,
so the idea would be we would still do
micro front ends,
but we'll be doing React micro front ends.
So
We'll have a homepage front end project.
We'll have an orders project,
a shipment project.
And then we'll have to figure out a way
to handle the routing from within the
React home application to route to the
different applications.
There are quite a bit of strategies
around that we'll have to talk about
beyond the back end stuff.
There can be some conflicts within
routing. I've been doing some research on,
you know, micro front ends with React.
It's not something I've done in React
before. I've done it in Angular before,
but not React.
Just.
So there will be some strategies that
we'll have to figure out around how we're
And.
going to do routing. You know, typically,
to give you an example, typically every...
micro front end will have an index, right?
Well, if all of them have an index,
there could be conflicts there.
So you have to figure out a strategy
around that.
And then there's the back end stuff.
So each micro front end will have to have
connect to the back end APIs,
and then we'll have to decide how we're
going to do that.
So I think that's kind of what this
meeting is about.
No.
So there's definitely some
Thank you.
Beyond the generation of the React code
itself,
there are quite a bit of things that
we're going to have to figure out how
we're going to handle.
Thomas,
I would like to take a minute actually.
Thanks for providing the detail, Thomas.
Yesterday,
evening after we had a meeting with
Manuela, you and myself,
so I had been back and looked at
Manuela's code and I did an extensive
Yep.
homework yesterday evening.
I just wanted to take 10 minutes and then
just present the challenges.
But still that homework,
so I was going to set up a call on Monday
morning,
but still I'm in the process of doing an
extensive analysis. But before that,
I would just like to flash my screen and
then present my findings.
Whatever I have done the research so far,
the detailed meeting is to follow.
Let me quickly share my screen actually.
Let me know when you see my screen.
I see it.
Okay, so yeah,
so I kind of from yesterday's meeting,
Visible.
what I understood was, yeah.
So this, yeah,
I think let me know when you, yeah.
So from yesterday's meeting,
what I understood was that this is the
proposed architecture that we are looking,
right?
So we would like to develop a new React
host shell app,
and then the shipment orders and carrier
application will be in React.
And the tracking and user management will
be in Angular. That is the proposed.
Well,
the React host is what is what Manuela
has already created. That's the host.
That, that.
That, but that is not micro front end.
Well, it can be. I mean,
the code that was generated from that,
the outer shell with the header bar and
the sidebar and then the main bar,
Mhm.
that is, I mean, it is the basic.
We're going to have to rework it to be a
Mhm.
micro front end,
but it would be the homepage micro front
end, the shell, right?
We'll have to pull some of the pieces
Yes, yeah, yeah, yeah.
that were created,
like the placeholders for shipment and
orders and carriers.
We'll have to replace those with the
actual routing to shipment orders and
carriers,
but the outer shell pieces will still
stay the same. Does that make sense?
Yeah, yeah, yep, yep.
So that's been built.
We just have to modify it to make it an
actual micro front end.
Yes,
and one thing I see the problem was like
the routing, as you mentioned,
the routing would be a problem if we go
with that route. And also,
if we have that React and Angular host
together, the browser, that Angular,
the core files,
that the Angular libraries and the React
libraries,
both we will have to do and that will
have some impact.
but yet I still have to do some kind of
POC to see whether this statement is true,
but it looks like we will have like the
mix and match of the React host,
React host and Angular will have some
impact on the page. And also,
and it looks like a hot sharing is also a
fragile workaround.
And if we have to share the states
between two,
application, we will have a challenge.
It looks like there are few.
Well, I don't think we're going to have,
the only thing that we'd have to share
state on would be the token, right?
That would be the only thing.
We would, yes, yes,
that would be the token.
Other than that,
I don't necessarily know that there's
going to be mixed state across the
different, you know,
the different applications.
And really when we think about the
Angular piece of it,
tracking is really the only one, right?
That's the one that we currently have in
prod that is all angular that we would
have to come out a way around to figure
out how to do that, right?
And that's if we don't if we don't
regenerate the tracking application from
Figma designs in and of itself and then
reuse the back end services that they
built for tracking, so.
But I agree with you.
That is definitely going to be something
we're going to have to POC and see how
well that works out. Because I've, yeah,
Exactly, yeah, we will have to.
mixing the two,
it's not something I've done before.
So you said you had,
but you've done it the other way.
You mixed React into Angular.
And then just to give everybody an idea,
you know,
if you're not familiar with the two
things. So
React does not consider itself to be a
framework. It's A JavaScript library,
right?
So that means that it is just a UI
JavaScript library.
And if there's other things that you need
to do, you pull in other libraries,
such as routing,
such as back-end services,
things like that,
or you build them in JavaScript,
or you use a library.
Whereas Angular is a full around
framework.
It has those things built into it.
It has routing in it.
It has database interactivity,
things like that, you know, API calls,
you know,
the ability to call APIs and things like
that.
So there are some definitely considerable
differences between the two.
And so there are going to be some things
that we're going to have to look at
potentially.
you know,
adding to the React to be able to support
some of the features that we want to do.
And yeah,
I think earlier in my career I worked as
a React developer for two years, Thomas.
So what I did was, see,
there is no stat state management current.
I just looked at the code actually. See,
whatever the UX,
the JSX files that we see,
the UX is perfectly, it's amazing.
Whatever the Figma JSX files we have used
it,
I don't see a Redux or any kind of React
Redux state management.
management is currently following the
code. Okay,
I agree. Yep.
so we definitely have to have a state
management and also the props that in the
react actually when I'm having a button
actually it should be bounded to the
props actually,
but none of the code has been bounded to
the props and there is no TypeScript at
all. Everything is a JSX file.
That is correct.
And that is embedded in the back end.
That is, see, everything is a JSX files,
which contains a business logic,
UI data and everything together. Okay,
but I see UX is perfect and it is like
all JSX code.
But is this ready for production?
But I think there is no react.
I think we need to modify the React code
in such a way that it should be
production ready,
meaning without state management,
we cannot go.
Because when I bind a back end
application itself,
the state management is the main thing
that we have to do in React. And also,
we have to find out that services layer
wherein we will have, say,
year earlier I have used Axios or some
kind.
kind of a service layer or back end
framework should be there,
Correct.
I should be in a position to call the
back end APIs.
That is also not that that framework was
not there.
And there is no separation of concern.
And also how we did the React development
earlier was we will have a mock data and
we will have a testing framework.
Whenever we do some changes, right,
we will just make sure we do the changes
in the mock data and we run the complete
test so that the user.
UI doesn't break.
That is how we promoted the code earlier,
but I don't see not even a single test
cases with the mock data or any,
not even a single karma or some kind of
Jasmine.
I think earlier I used to Jasmine
actually,
Yep.
but I think now we have a lot of
frameworks available and that is not
there. See, the POC is good and yes,
we can take it to the market,
but it is just still,
I feel that it is just the JSX file.
to the UI,
but there is no React architecture or
there is no React code is being followed
as what we will have to generate the
complete code or we will have to give a
prompt if at all we were planning to go
with the React, right?
We will have to come up with a complete
architecture to enhance how to generate
the code so that it will be a
full-fledged application.
And also there is no pagination and
That is,
that is a concept of lazy loading.
I agree with you there.
It is a UX.
The prototype is absolutely amazing. Yes,
it is.
I would still consider it still has a UX
code,
but I think we need to consider all this
if it has to be a production ready.
OK, a lot of work needs to be done. See,
it doesn't say, as you say,
it doesn't matter whether we go with the
Angular or React.
Okay, but the code,
whatever we have right now,
though we say it is like ready to ship,
it's not even go to the production.
When we integrate it back end itself,
right?
Without the React Redux and without the
service layer,
we cannot even integrate the back end API.
We will have to revisit.
This is one thing actually.
But we have to know a lot of changes to
the code. And also apart from that,
we will have to consider all these issues
because the routing and routing is a big
thing and routing is a big thing.
Everybody is saying we will have to do a
POC,
how we will handle Angular and React
routing. See, given the time yesterday,
even I just had a little bit of shorter
time.
Maybe I can work on a little bit on the
weekend and do some homework and then
come back come back with a detailed
analysis of how the React coded standard
and everything should be followed.
I can still do my analysis,
but I just wanted to present it,
still present it today before we talk
about the back end strategy. This is like,
I'm half the way in working on it
actually. I'm yet to start a POC also.
So I just wanted to get my thoughts,
Thomas, before we start this meeting.
Yeah, I mean, like I said,
there is a lot that we have to talk about
Are you with me?
around leveraging React, right?
Like you said, state management,
we need to figure that out. API layers,
we need to figure that out, right?
Testing, automated testing,
we have to figure that out.
All of this stuff that you have here are
things that we need to think about, right?
It's easy to create a POC.
It's another thing to create a
production-ready application.
Exactly, that's what I wanted to make.
So if that is the case,
so one thing I was doing in another
analysis was yesterday after talking to
Manuela, that Figma Connect, right?
Why we say that, yes, all the AI code,
either we take a cloud or we take a
cursor, we take a Devin,
all the AI tools have an edge over React.
because all these models are trained more
towards React,
there are less availability on the
Angular. So whatever the tool,
it is going to generate a better code for
React. Actually, that is a one H.
But coming to that Figma Connect,
I did a little bit of research on the
Figma Connect.
So when we are taking the JXX files,
right, we need to.
to kind of write a mapper and tell LLM
how to convert that JSX to the two-way
binding for Angular file.
If we train the LLM to do that kind of
analysis, right?
And it is easy to generate the Angular
code also.
But as I said earlier,
I need a little bit of time to do a POC,
how to convert that Figma code connector
so that we can train or we could provide
samples so that the Figma code,
the JSX that we are getting,
we can convert it to a two-way binding
with the Angular code so that we could
generate the code in Angular also.
If we prove that, we can,
so we can avoid all these issues that I'm
showing in this presentation.
That is one way to go about it,
but still we have to do a POC.
But the second thing is that, see,
we are in the assumption that or maybe
shipping to market,
I totally understand all the AI tools
have edge.
towards React,
but still it is not a production ready
code. We need to prompt or we need to,
even if we are using the AI tools,
we need to make sure that all these
architectural concerns and everything has
been followed when we are generating a
code. Otherwise, it will be a nightmare,
not even go to production.
When we are integrating with the back end
API itself, it will be nightmare is what.
From my experience, I'm thinking.
Yeah, I agree with you.
Okay, yeah, thanks. Thanks, Thomas.
I just wanted to take this moment and
then present it before.
I think I'll set up a call sometime on
Monday to go over this along with some
kind of POC,
maybe Monday or maybe probably I'm
thinking on Monday,
I'll come up with more details. Okay,
yeah, thank you.
Yeah.
I think Janardhana has a question.
Yeah, Thomas,
I just have a general question regarding
how does it all work, right? See,
I said POC is good, we can see all these,
but there are a lot of things in the back
end that needs to drive the rules and
need to bring it in the front, right?
So are we going to do piece by piece or
is it like we're going to build the front
end and then slowly do the back end and
then connect?
then one by one,
how is it all going to work?
Well, typically what we want to do,
that's why we want to do micro front ends.
Typically the, like,
let's say take orders, for example,
we would be building the UI components
for order at the same time that we're
building the back end services for order,
right? The same for carrier.
We would be doing each of the individual
domains,
we'd be building the micro front ends at
the same time that we're building the
back end so that the
The 2 teams can work in conjunction with
each other to build the UI components and
the APIs that are needed for those
components.
Yeah, it looks like the way, you know,
it looks like the design is already ready,
right? So my understanding is...
The front end might come out pretty quick
because of all the tools that is
available and the design that is there.
But the back end,
which needs to support the front end in
terms of data and getting that
information from the API and all those
things, would take a longer time, right?
Right. So I mean,
obviously we still have we have teams
that are working on the back end side of
it, which is our back end,
our back end services,
the technology has not changed.
We're still using Java and Spring Boot
with AWS RDS databases or Oracle
databases is needed, right,
depending on the services, right? So
You know,
if it's if it's new data that we're that
we're supporting,
then it's an AWS RDS database.
If it's existing data,
such as some of the, you know,
some of the master data tables that we
didn't want to have to recreate,
we are just directly,
we have a new master data service that's
reading the tables from TMS's Oracle
database for those.
There are things that we just can't get
from, you know,
that we didn't want to recreate from a
master data perspective,
so we've decided to use the Oracle
databases for those.
Okay, so.
But the UI, the UI components are,
you know,
it's taking a Figma design and creating a
JavaScript UI for it, right? I mean,
that's basically what it is,
and we're using, you know,
Correct.
Manuela created a process of creating the
designs in Figma and then using using MCP
Model Context Protocol.
which is a way of connecting an AI model
to Figma to generate UI code.
And then also with that,
there is the ability to do some checking
Correct.
to make sure that what you created
actually is the same thing that what you
designed, right?
And I think that's the piece where the
React comes in really well.
that Angular doesn't have.
So you can't do that check to make sure
that the component that you built,
the button, the list, the whatever,
looks like what you've designed.
And so that was one of the main reasons
that the decision was to go with React
was because Manuela has built that
process of not only generating the code,
but also being able to
to check to make sure the code looks like
and is exactly like what was designed in
Figma.
Okay.
But,
and as and and and and we brought this up
and and and and again,
Hema just brought this up,
there are other pieces around,
not just the UI components themselves,
not just the buttons,
the the the you know, the the the list,
the buttons, the things like that.
There are a lot of pieces within building
a UI that you need to to take into
account.
State management is a very important one.
Do we need to manage state,
such as if you load a list of something,
do we need to pass that list around from
one component, one page to another page?
Or are there pieces of the things that we
need to pass around from them? The user,
you know, the user who's, you know,
who's logged in,
do we need to pass their credentials from
page to page to page as we click through,
as we click through the different...
the different, you know, micro front ends.
And so you need state management to do
that. Also,
you need the ability to call the back end
APIs from the React code. So like, like,
like Hema said,
typically you use something like Axios to
do that,
which is another JavaScript library.
That would give you the ability to call
the back end.
So,
you have to add that to React to be able
to do that,
and then there's the ability to do unit
testing or automated unit testing,
where you actually run through and make
sure that every component you built is
unit tested, that it, you know,
it conforms to the standards that you
want, and then it also is, you know,
it tests correctly.
So there's other things around just the
generating of the UI components that make
something production ready.
And then there's all the CICD stuff and
all that,
the building and deploying it in AWS.
Yes, Manuela.
Okay, um...
Let's talk step by step.
There is a lot that I need to follow up
Yep.
on that. But...
First of all, yes,
we have data binding with different
components that change data,
like they are binding it to each other,
right? We have it in shipments,
we have it in the new.
in the new global search that we are
doing. That's what's happening.
So it's not as loose as you are actually
saying. Yes, the thing,
the only thing that I still missing is
the structure to connect to a database.
But that's because I was trying to
request access through the database.
Actually,
business and shipment told us that it
would be better to have real data in this
prototype.
So I was trying to get access for that,
but it's really difficult, guys.
I don't know why it's too bureaucratic.
And I just need documentation and
understanding. And
That's it.
Nothing else to being able to solve this.
It doesn't need to be a big problem.
As I said initially,
we have to sort things out.
It's on our on our on our choice that
that process is going to take a lot or
not.
So you were trying to get access to the
databases or the APIs?
I'm maybe I missed it.
The API, the API, sorry,
the APIs to have real data and to,
OK.
Yep.
but more than that, trying to understand.
because you have all this documented,
right?
You have all this architecture backend
wise. So I'm trying to get downstanding,
but it's really difficult because the
only thing that I've got is a CSV file.
And that's not actually, you know, it's,
we need better communication, I think.
Well, and Manuela,
I'm going to be perfectly honest with you.
I didn't even know you were doing the UI,
redoing the UI until about a month and a
half ago. So I mean, the communication is,
you know,
Yeah.
there is a lot of communication
breakdowns across the org overall, right?
So
Yeah, of course.
I mean,
I think that that is that not just,
I mean, obviously,
we've had teams that were working on
orders and shipments and things like that.
And if there's somebody that you need to
connect with to get an API or something
to be able to do what you want.
I.
But I mean, beyond that,
I think that some of the things that
Hemalatha has brought up are very
important, right? I mean,
React by default is one way binding,
right? It's so.
you read data from an API and it loads
into the virtual DOM, right? Or the DOM.
And it does, you know,
it doesn't manage state.
So if you change something in there,
then it doesn't get written back to the
back end database.
It doesn't call an API and write that.
It's single one-way binding, right?
We need to talk about that.
We need to understand what UIs are going
to have to have two-way binding.
How are we going to solve that problem?
Orders would be one, right?
We have an order form.
We're going to have to have two-way
binding on that, right?
There are things that we need to talk
about beyond just how the screens look
and feel.
There's going to have to be real data
behind them,
and we're going to have to understand how
we manage those things.
Is a.
And I know Thomas,
I would like to add one point here.
Yes, sugar, let's.
Without the state management and without
the Taxios integration,
I think we need to talk about that before
even we go further with the AC API
integration. I can just using the JSX,
I can integrate an API and then fetch the
data from database and then show it in
the React application.
That is not the goal here, right?
And the whole purpose of having an
No.
enterprise application is like.
How am I going to do a state management?
Because applications like a shipments,
Yeah.
we cannot go without the state management.
And I think without the state management,
there is, I think React application,
Bye.
it will be a night.
I think we cannot go with that without it.
So are we trying to list problems or are
we trying to solve them? Like,
Well,
I think we need a list of problems before
I'm not really...
we can try to solve them, right? I mean,
we need a list of the challenges that
Exactly, exactly.
we're going to run into beyond.
So when you think about what Manuela has
created,
which takes the designs and creates a
basic React front end, right? But
There's a lot of to an enterprise
application beyond just the look and feel
of the front end.
There's a lot of pieces that we have to
talk about.
And then we're going to have to figure
out how we're going to solve those
problems, right?
And I think we have to understand what
the problems we're going to run into
before we can actually start picking it.
Like state management,
we can decide we want to go with Redux.
Redux comes with its own challenges.
Redux is not easy.
And somebody who's never done Redux
before is going to have a lot of problems
with Redux. It's not easy to manage Redux.
It's a whole thing in and of itself.
And then we have to decide,
do we want to build a Redux, you know,
a state management for all of the micro
front ends, right?
Are we going to have to manage state
across all of the micro front ends?
So that means we have to build
the state management as the main and the
main application,
and then somehow figure out how to manage
that across multiple micro front ends.
There's a lot of challenges there.
We have to figure that part out.
And we're going to have to solve that.
Two-way data binding,
that's another thing. Obviously,
the Redux can handle that because you're
managing state in Redux, but you know,
we'll have to figure those pieces out.
Pagination, we'll have to figure that out.
You know, you know, API,
how we're going to manage different
environments, properties, files,
things like that.
Those are things we're going to have to
figure.
There's a lot of challenges that we're
going to have to figure out.
beyond the basic designs and the basic
creation of the look and feel of the
application.
So I think what we need to do is we need
to start,
OK, let.
we need to start figuring out what the
problems we're going to,
what are the challenges that we're going
to have to come up with and then figure
out a solve for them.
Okay, let's start solving then.
Well,
I think what Hemalatha and I was wanting
Yeah.
to do,
and Hemalatha was going to come up with a
list of what we think the challenges are,
and then we can start have,
we can have a meeting and discuss them
and start coming up with solutions to
them.
I don't necessarily know if doing that in
Okay.
an ad hoc way like this is going to make
sense.
It probably makes more sense for me and
Hemalatha to go
off and come up with what we think are
the problem,
the challenges we're going to run into
and then come back and discuss them.
Would you agree, Hemalatha?
Yeah, I understood you.
I think I was going to, yeah,
thanks Thomas. Yeah,
I think we are on the same page.
Yeah.
So you're going to discuss the challenges,
isn't that what was in the PowerPoint?
We're going to get,
we're going to create the list.
We're going to create the list of the
challenges,
and then we can discuss the solutions to
them.
Okay,
so the PowerPoint is not comprehensive is
what you're saying.
Exactly, I will just, yeah,
given the time yesterday, yeah,
Not yet, right? I mean,
we just went through it yesterday,
so yesterday was the first day we went.
yesterday evening only I spent it.
With five of us,
I think I analyzing the code and then
doing some,
this is what I can come up with five
hours of my work.
I need to spend some more time to come up
with a comprehensive list to go over.
Yeah. And then we can discuss,
and I don't necessarily know if we need
everybody on this call in those meetings
to discuss the solutions to it.
We probably need a base list of people to
come up with them, right? You know,
Yup.
and there were things that Hemalatha has
on hers that I'm going to add,
Yeah.
I'm going to add to her list also.
Routing is a big one.
I don't know if you had that on there or
not.
I think I have it, Thomas.
The.
Okay, yeah.
But I have it at level,
but you can add it. Yeah,
I'll share the presentation.
But the work in progress presentation,
you can add it.
Yep.
So I think what would make sense for me
and Hemalatha to go off and build our
list and then for us to come back and
discuss it.
What timeline are we looking at for that?
I would say early next week.
Would you agree?
Okay.
Nima.
Yeah, yeah, sure, Thomas.
A yearly next week should work out.
All right, so let's...
We don't have Laurie Thomas.
Are you scheduling that?
Yeah, I'll schedule it.
Yeah, I'll schedule it. Yeah.
OK.
That's a good plan.
Okay.
In the meantime, Manuela,
would it help for you to get that access
to the APIs?
Yeah, of course. I mean,
if you want to pull me in those meetings,
I'll be glad to.
No,
I'm at the API access you requested a
while back.
You.
Oh yeah, yeah, of course.
I still need those anyways for shipments.
SLNU.
Right, no,
I think the the is already there in the
So.
LLD,
and I think I can share you that Viki
links where we have all those.
Okay, yeah.
We're having a hard time understanding
you, Saikat. You said you share the links.
I'll share the Wiki links where we have
all the API endpoints, request response,
everything.
Okay.
Big.
Okay. Thank you, Saikat.
Okay.
Awesome. All right. Thanks, everybody.
Thanks, Saikat.
Thank you.
Bye.